The Spectacular Adventure Continues!
Aladdin and the King of Thieves is a adventure,
animation, family film directed by Tad Stones.
Legendary secrets are revealed as Aladdin and his friends—Jasmine, Abu, Carpet and, of course, the always entertaining Genie—face all
sorts of terrifying threats and make some exciting last-minute escapes pursuing the King Of Thieves and his villainous crew.
Aladdin (voice), played by Scott Weinger.
Aladdin (singing voice), played by Brad Kane.
Genie (voice), played by Robin Williams.
Jasmine (voice), played by Linda Larkin.
Jasmine (singing voice), played by Liz Callaway.
Cassim (voice), played by John Rhys-Davies.
Aladdin and the King of Thieves (stylized as Aladdin and The King of Thieves Starring Robin Williams on the first edition) is a 1996 American
direct-to-video animated musical fantasy adventure film produced by Walt Disney Television Animation and Disney Video Premiere.
It is the second sequel to Disney's 1992 animated feature film Aladdin, and it serves as the final chapter and installment of the Arabian Nights-inspired Disney
franchise beginning with the first film, and continuing with its first direct-to-video sequel The Return of Jafar and the animated television series.
The film takes place after the third season of the television series and is inspired by the tale Ali Baba
and the Forty Thieves from One Thousand and One Nights, replacing Ali Baba with Aladdin.
For the first time since the original Aladdin, the film has a completely new soundtrack instead of
the rearranged music from the original film for The Return of Jafar and the series.
This film also marks the return of Robin Williams, reprising his role as Genie (Dan
Castellaneta voices him in the second film, the series and other media).
Although this film serves as the series finale of the television series, the characters also appear in a 1999 crossover episode of the animated series Hercules, titled "Hercules and the Arabian
Night", as well as the segment More Than a Peacock Princess from the 2007 direct-to-video film Disney Princess Enchanted Tales: Follow Your Dreams, both of which occur after this plot.
The film received mixed-to-negative reviews, although it was
deemed an improvement over The Return of Jafar.
The film explores themes of flying carpet, musical, sequel, orient, genie.